花仙女王
费雪小姐探案集
我肯定教过这些姑娘们要准时啊
I'm sure I taught those girls punctuality.
需要我等其余女孩来了再上第一道菜么 小姐
Should I delay the first course for our other maidens,Miss?
不用 上菜吧 巴特勒先生 时间就是金钱啊
No,forge ahead,Mr Butler. Every moment counts.
现在 假设你们正坐在市长晚宴的餐桌上
Now,you're seated at the Mayoral Supper
第一道菜刚刚上来
and you've just been served your first course.
你们该选什么餐具?
What is your weapon of choice?
呃 这是食鱼刀
Well,that's a fish knife.
- 但这不是鱼 - 正确
- But that's not a fish. - Correct.
而且应该是从外向内的顺序用
And I know it's from the outside in.
但这个问题可能有陷阱
But it's a trick question.
- 那我放弃了 - 绝佳的选择 玛丽
- I give up,then. - Excellent choice,Marie.
芦笋是完全可以用手抓食的
Asparagus is perfectly acceptable finger food,
只要没浸在酱汁里或煮的稀烂就行
provided it's not drowned in sauce or overcooked
还有 只要学着晚宴主人的吃法就没错
and as long as you take your lead from your host or your hostess.
下一道菜...
Next course...
你又上了社会版了 小姐
You made the social pages again,Miss.
- 花仙女王 - 哦!
- Queen Of The Flowers. - Oh!
"花朵节将以由市政厅举办的"
"The festival will culminate in a supper dance"
"晚宴舞会隆重结束"
"hosted by the Town Hall"
"届时 这些身世坎坷的女孩们
"at which these young unfortunates
将在费雪小姐的专家级指导下"
will blossom into flower maidens"
蜕变为花仙小姐
"and demonstrate the grace and poise"
尽情展现她们的魅力和风姿"
acquired under Miss Fisher's expert tutelage."
我们还剩几天时间?
How many days do we have left?
四天 四天半
Four. And a half.
要是四年半可能更好
Four and a half years might be more useful.
对不起我迟到了 费雪小姐 我没赶上车
Sorry I'm late,Miss Fisher. I missed my tram.
电车跟你一块去了海滩了吗?
Did your tram happen to follow you to the foreshore?
我今天早上本来要在海边见凯蒂
I was meant to meet Kitty at the bathing boxes this morning
但是我没找到她
but I couldn't find her.
不用脱外套了 萝丝
Leave your coat on,Rose.
我们要去找我们的失踪少女
We're going in search of our missing maiden.
来吧 女士们 去海边
Come on,ladies. Beach.
与其说是训练年轻女士还不如说是赶羊
This job is more like rounding up sheep than grooming young ladies.
- 费雪小姐! - 又怎么了?
- Miss Fisher! - What now?
都退后 姑娘们
Stand back,girls!
- 哦 不! - 是凯蒂
- Oh,no. - It's Kitty.
她还有呼吸吗?
Is she breathing?
- 没了 - 圣母玛利亚
- Nothing. - Holy Mary,Mother of God.
但她很会游泳啊
But she was a good swimmer.
我们去野餐的时候
When we went for the picnic,
她游到了码头而且差点比你还快 小姐
she swam to the pier and almost beat you,Miss.
- 我记得 - 她一定是自杀的 你们说呢
- I remember. - She must have drowned herself,don't you think?
淹死自己没那么容易 玛丽
It's not that easy to drown yourself,Marie.
对吗 小姐?
Is it,Miss?
也许她在自己的口袋里装满了石头
Well,maybe she filled her pockets full of stones.
她没有口袋 玛丽
She didn't have pockets,Marie.
姑娘们
Girls.
你觉得她在水里待多久了 警官?
How long do you think she's been in the water,sir?
根据她的皮肤状况推断应该时间很久了
By the look of her skin,a good few hours.
可能是一整晚
Maybe overnight.
也许费雪小姐能提供点信息
Perhaps Miss Fisher can enlighten us.
你这儿其它的女孩子还好吗?
How are your other maidens bearing up?
她们都不是省油的灯 包括简
They're tough customers,including Jane.
要唬住她们真不容易 但我想这案子奏效了
Takes a lot to shock them but I think this has done the trick.
你有什么想法?
What are your thoughts?
她死的时候可是穿戴整齐
The fact that she was fully dressed?
划船事故
A boating accident.
你不用跟我玩幽默 杰克
You don't need to humour me,Jack.
她前一天晚上就穿着那身衣服
She was dressed from the evening before
晚上可没人敢划船
when the foreshore is a less friendly place.
我们还没联系上她的家人
We haven't been able to contact her next of kin.
我想她就是举目无亲
I don't think she had any.
这些女孩都是长期住在福利院里的
All of the girls have spent a great deal of time in welfare
除了萝丝
apart from Rose.
我审案子的时候你能来旁听吗?
Do you think you could sit in on my interviews?
你是在邀请我吗?
Are you actually inviting me?
我很乐于和愤怒的码头工或者无赖恶棍打交道
I'm happy to deal with angry wharfies and trigger-happy thugs
但是碰到反复无常的少女时
but I will bow to your expertise
我不得不臣服于你了
when it comes to wayward teenage girls.
你知道凯蒂住哪吗 卫兰小姐?
Do you know where Kitty lived,Miss Whelan?
不知道 她说她原来是个洗衣女仆
No idea. She said she used to be a laundry maid.
她穿的不像个穷女仆 不是吗?
She didn't dress like a maid,did she?
看看那身艳紫色的连衣裙和金闪闪的鞋子
Her frock all shiny purple and those golden shoes?
她最近有什么伤心事么?
Had she seemed upset about anything lately?
也许有吧
Maybe.
那你觉得是什么事?
About what,do you think?
- 我只是瞎猜 - 好的
- Well,I'd be guessing. - Alright.
你猜她是怎么了?
What do you imagine was wrong with her?
我猜她是被一个迷了眼的男孩伤了心
Well,I imagine her heart was broke by some starry-eyed boy
那男孩可能突然改变心意 爱上别人
who came back to his true mind
凯蒂失望之下找不到生存的意义了
and so Kitty had no reason to breathe another breath
于是深海之歌召唤了她
and the song of the black ocean called her.
我就是这么猜的
That's what I guess.
那我猜你读了太多廉价的惊险小说了
And I guess you've been reading too many penny dreadfuls.
谢谢你 玛丽
Thank you,Marie.
希望她刚顺走的钢笔对你没什么特殊意义
I hope you weren't attached to that fountain pen.
我不清楚到底凯蒂有没有烦心事
I don't know if anything was bothering Kitty.
不过上周她突然晕倒在了大厅
But she collapsed in the hall last week.
我没注意到啊
I wasn't aware of that.
她不想让费雪小姐知道
She didn't want Miss Fisher to know.
她怕你改变主意 不让她做花仙小姐了
In case you changed your mind about her being a flower maiden.
就因为她身体不适?
Because she wasn't well?
打扰了 警官
Excuse me,sir.
委员会说这是凯蒂・佩斯的住址
The council gave this as Kitty Pace's address.
"巴拉克拉瓦区 蒙特莱大道15号"
"15 Montclair Avenue,Balaclava.'
但这是萝丝家啊
But that's where Rose lives.
巴拉克拉瓦区 蒙特莱大道?
Montclair Avenue,Balaclava?
- 是我家 - 凯蒂填的也是这个地址
- That's right. - The same details Kitty gave to the Council.
洗衣女仆 巴拉克拉瓦区 蒙特莱大道15号
Laundry maid. 15,Montclair Avenue,Balaclava.
这是很久以前的事了 我和凯蒂还不太熟
That was ages ago. I didn't know Kitty very well then.
但你们住在一起
But you lived at the same address.
我爷爷雇了她做洗衣女仆
My grandfather employed her as a laundry maid.
今天早上你本来约了她准备做什么?
What were you planning on doing this morning? When you arranged to meet?
没什么事
Nothing.
凯蒂昨晚打电话说要见我一面
Kitty telephoned me last night and she asked me to meet her.
她遇到什么麻烦了吗?
Was she in some kind of trouble?
有人找她麻烦了吗?
Was anyone bothering her?
她没提到
Not that she said.
谢谢你 萝丝 你能在客厅等我一下吗?
Thank you,Rose. Would you please wait for me in the parlour?
为什么你会选中萝丝?
Why is Rose one of your lucky maidens?
她看起来没什么竞争力
She doesn't seem like a battler.
她爷爷是弗朗克林・维斯顿
Her grandfather is Franklin Weston.
维斯顿百货公司原来就是他们家的
They used to own Weston's department stores.
但很显然 现在他已经落败养不起她了
But apparently,she's become too much for him to handle.
外面有个女人 一直盯着咱们屋里
There's a lady out there staring at the house.
好事不出门 坏事传千里
It doesn't take long for bad news to spread.
不用管她
Take no notice.
罗宾逊探长已经讯问完女孩们了 桃乐西
Inspector Robinson has finished with the girls for now,Dot.
市长办公室刚打电话过来
And the Mayor's office telephoned.
他还在市政厅等你的排练
He's still waiting at the hall for your rehearsals.
哦 天呐
Oh,dear.
罗宾逊探长说可以把萝丝捎回家
Inspector Robinson's offered to give Rose a lift home
我把赛斯和伯特叫来送玛丽了
and I've got Cec and Bert calling by for Marie.
我们不上舞蹈课了么?
What about our dance lesson?
不是说好要练习队形
We were meant to practise the procession
赢得"花仙小姐"的嘛
and getting our Flower Maidens prize.
我想今天的艰巨任务已经够多了 玛丽
I think we've all had enough challenges for today,Marie.
来吧
Come along.
玛丽
Marie.
开信刀拿来
Letter opener.
我要去市政厅见市长
I'm going to go in and see the Mayor.
- 和我一块去吗? - 不 谢谢
- Coming with me? - No,no,thank you.
我要待在屋里 我要待在家里
I'll stay inside,I'll stay here.
是我啊 爷爷!
Only me,Grandpa!
我是探长杰克・罗宾逊 这是警探科林斯
Detective Inspector Jack Robinson,sir,and Constable Collins.
我是弗朗克林・D・维斯顿
I'm Franklin D Weston.
很高兴见到你们
Pleased to make your acquaintance.
要来点什么茶点吗?
Can I offer you some kind of refreshment?
不用了 谢谢
Ah,no thank you.
今天早上我们在圣基尔达海滩发现一起溺水案
We attended a drowning this morning at St Kilda foreshore.
死者是您孙女的一个朋友
The girl was a friend of your granddaughter's,
花仙小姐之一 叫凯瑟琳・佩斯
one of the flower maidens,Katherine Pace.
你记得凯蒂吧?
You remember Kitty?
萝丝说你曾经雇用过她
Rose tells us you employed her for a time.
是这样的
Yes,that's right,so I did.
不过 六个月前我让她走了
But I had to let her go,oh,about six months ago.
她的工作 呃 怎么说 达不到一定标准吧
Her work just,well,wasn't up to standard.
不过她人倒是不错
But she was a nice enough young lady,though.
你说她淹死了?
Drowned,you said?
- 是意外吗? - 我们目前还不清楚
- Was it an accident? - We're not sure at this stage.
您知道凯蒂离开这以后去哪了吗
Do you know where Kitty moved on to after she left this address.
她有什么朋友家人之类的么?
Any friends or family you might know of?
我不知道她是不是找到下家了
I'm not sure if she found herself a new employer
我当时还给她写了封推荐信呢
but I did write her a good reference at the time.
但是她没拿就走了
Yes,she left without taking it with her.
应该就在这边
I should have it here somewhere.
探长
Sir.
看电话线
Telephone wire.
别找了 爷爷 这帮不上忙
I don't think that will help,Grandpa.
没事的 维斯顿小姐
It's quite alright,Miss Weston.
谢谢你的酒
Thank you.
如果您想起任何有关此案的线索
And if you do remember any handy details about Miss Pace,
请打电话到警察局
please contact the police station.
希望凶手早日落网
Let's hope the perpetrator is caught and punished
- 并受到严惩 - 我们会尽力的 先生
- with the full force of the law. - We'll do our best,sir.
刚才观察的很到位嘛 警探
Nice work on the telephone,Constable.
谢谢夸奖
Thank you,sir.
这房子想必经历了兴衰吧
This house has definitely seen better days.
联络电信邮政局
Contact the Post Master General's department.
查一下这个电话什么时候断线的
Find out if the phone's been disconnected.
这是一条线索吗 探长
Will that help us,sir?
要是早就断线了 凯蒂还怎么可能给萝丝打电话
It will be if it was before Rose Weston claims Kitty rang her.
再往上点 一点就行...
Just up,that's a bit high...
往左移一点 好的
A bit to the left,good.
好了 完美
Yes,perfect.
我的上帝啊 可怜的姑娘
Goodness gracious! Poor girl.
到底发生了什么
I wonder what happened.
哦 您见过我的外甥了么 费雪小姐?
Oh,have you met my nephew,Miss Fisher?
他叫德里克・菲利普斯
Derek Phillips.
见过了 上次跳狐步舞你帮忙来着
Yes,you helped out with the fox trot.
我们在学校有国标和摩登舞课 我很乐意帮忙
We do ballroom and modern at Grammar. I was happy to lend a hand.
我们知道她家境贫寒卑微
I know she came from the wrong side of the tracks but she...
但她不是个傻姑娘啊
She wasn't a stupid girl.
真可惜啊 浪费了这一切
It'll be a shame to waste all this.
其他女孩会理解的
The other girls will have to understand.
我们不能取消晚餐舞会
We can't cancel the Supper Dance.
你不觉得应该取消舞会?
You don't think we should?
以表对死者的尊敬么?
Out of respect?
我觉得正因如此反而更该办这场舞会
Don't you feel it's all the more reason to forge ahead?
我是说 女孩们各个都不容易
I mean,these girls lead difficult lives
这是个好机会一展风采啊
and this is their chance to shine.
她们的苦我也能理解 费雪小姐
We understand them,Miss Fisher.
谁也不是天生权贵
None of us were born to privilege.
玛乔丽 在门口再放一面委员会的旗帜吧
Marjorie? I think we need another Council banner over the entrance.
她们走在街上都要担心自身安危
I do question the point of teaching them social graces
我实在不知为何还要费劲学这些社交礼仪?
when they can't even walk the streets safely.
你教她们什么都可以 费雪小姐
Teach them what you want,Miss Fisher.
不过姑娘们日夜练习 翘首企盼
The girls have worked so hard and are so looking forward to it.
我们怎么忍心让她们失望呢
We can't disappoint them.
在想什么?
Penny for your thoughts.
我太幸运了能成为芙莱妮小姐家的一员
Just thinking how lucky I've been to end up with Miss Phryne.
还有我呢
And me.
我们还会继续幸运下去的 简
We're still lucky,Jane. Both of us.
我和芙莱妮小姐在一起真的很开心
I've had such a lovely time with her.
墨香书籍 锦衣玉食
with Books and new clothes
还有朝夕相伴的同窗挚友
and a wonderful school and friends,
还有巴特勒先生 赛斯和伯特
Mr Butler,and Cec and Bert.
还有你呢 桃乐西
And you,Dot.
无论未来如何 我都曾经拥有这些
Whatever happens,I've had all that.
未来你也能拥有啊 你这个小笨蛋
Nothing's going to happen. You funny thing.
电信邮政局已经确认过了
The Post Master General's department confirmed
维斯顿家的电话十个月前就已经断线了
that the Weston's telephone line was interrupted ten months ago,
由于家庭活在
by a house fire.
然后就再也没连上过么?
And the service was never restored?
是的 因为他们没有支付重连费用
No,because the reconnection bill was never paid.
所以说凯蒂死的当晚并不可能打电话给萝丝咯
So Kitty Pace couldn't have telephoned Rose the night she died.
是的 而且之前的火灾疑似纵火案
No,sir. And it seems the fire was a case of arson.
没有人处理此案
No-one was charged
不过维斯顿小姐被列为嫌疑人
but Miss Weston was listed as a person of interest.
好一位爱说瞎话 爱纵火的花仙小姐啊
Right. A liar,an arsonist and a flower maiden.
我开始感激费雪小姐给我带来的危机感了
I'm beginning to appreciate Miss Fisher's challenge.
我就知道你会来的 萝丝还说你不会呢
I knew you'd come. Rose said you wouldn't.
现在你还有心思跳舞?
How can you even think about dancing?
不想跳就走人 回你那富丽堂皇的别墅吧
Go home,then,to your nice big house...
计划变了 女士们 别想什么狐步舞了
Change of plan,ladies. Forget the fox trot.
- 你说过这很要紧的 - 我知道
- You said it mattered. - I know what I said.
而且我还非常相信女性
And I'm a great believer in the power of the feminine
具有改变这个文明世界的力量
to wield influence in the civilised world.
但发生在凯蒂身上的事可没这么文明
But whatever happened to Kitty wasn't very civilised.
这么说你觉得她不是自杀?
So you don't think she did herself in?
对
No.
而且我很后悔没有教给凯蒂
And I wish I could have taught Kitty something more useful
比跳舞和礼仪更有用的东西
than dancing or deportment or etiquette.
比如呢?
Like what?
脱掉外套吧 姑娘们 我来教你们
Take your coats off,ladies,and I'll show you.
来吧
Come on!
脱掉外套
Coats off!
想办法反击啊
Now,think hard.
做得好
Good choice!
现在又上来一个
Now here come another one.
用第一式
Manoeuvre one.
攻击下半身
Groin.
现在用第二式 锁喉!
Manoeuvre two - throat!
做得好!
Well done!
探长 原来费雪小姐会柔道啊
Miss Fisher knows judo,sir?
当然了
Of course.
- 现在怎么办? - 怎么办?
- Now what? - What?
- 经典桥段吊带袜上别匕首 - 小姐?
- The old dagger in the garter! - Miss?
你该不是在裙子底下藏了什么危险武器吧
I hope you're not concealing a dangerous weapon under that skirt.
我裙子底下的好东西多了 女人皆如此
I'm concealing a lot of things. That's what a lady does.
我和科林斯警探得问维斯顿小姐几个问题
Constable Collins and I need to ask Miss Weston a few more questions.
萝丝
Rose.
如果你真是最后一个见过凯蒂的人
If you were the last person to see or speak with Kitty before she died,
警察会不停审问你直到找到线索的
the police will keep on questioning you until they get somewhere.
凯蒂的确没给我打电话
Kitty didn't telephone me.
因为我们早已经有约定
Because we already had an arrangement...
每周五晚上都在浴池碰面
Friday nights we'd meet at the bathing sheds
然后一起坐电车
and then we'd catch the tram.
去哪?
Where to?
去月亮公园或者去金合欢公园跳舞
We'd go to Luna Park or we'd go dancing at Wattle Park.
有时我们甚至会去酒店坐坐
Sometimes we'd even go to a hotel.
我很喜欢这样 但凯蒂不想再陪我一起去了
I'd come all that way and Kitty didn't want to go out anymore.
她很生气
She was angry.
说我不了解她生活的艰辛
Told me I didn't know how hard her life was
- 就因为我住在大房子里 - 然后呢
- because I lived in a big house. - And?
我们吵了起来 她还推了我
We argued and she pushed me.
然后突然 她滑了一下 撞到了头
Then somehow she tripped and banged her head.
然后你怎么做了?
So what did you do?
我把她叫醒 然后跟她说我去找人帮忙
I woke her up,then told her I'd go and fetch some help.
但我回来的时候 她已经不在了
But when I came back,she was gone.
我以为她只是走开一下 马上就回来
I thought she must have come to or maybe she'd just come back.
所以我等了一整晚
So I waited all night.
但我发誓我不知道她怎么就落水了
But I don't know how she ended up in the water,I swear.
你会把我关起来么?
Are you going to lock me up?
暂时不会
That's enough for now.
萝丝 到那边和其他姑娘们一块等着吧?
Why don't you go and wait with the others,Rose?
我们会进行尸检
We'll see if the autopsy confirms
看看死者头部的伤痕是否和她描述的一致
a head injury consistent with her story.
我希望头上的伤不是致命原因
I just hope it doesn't confirm it as the cause of death.
你知道她是个纵火狂吗?
Did you know she was a pyromaniac?
- 这是消防队提供的资料 - 谢谢提醒
- According to the fire brigade. - Thank you.
我会看好自己的家的
I'll keep a close eye on my flammables.
小姐 你好
Hello,Miss.
简有访客在厨房里等着呢
Jane has a visitor waiting in the kitchen.
她等了你一个上午了
She's been here since this morning.
她说 她是你妈妈
She,um,claims to be your mother.
我没想到还能再见到她
I didn't think I'd ever see her again.
她肯定认不出我了
She won't recognise me.
这么多年没见
It's been too long.
她一定能认出你的
She'll recognise you.
你好 妈妈
Hello,Mother.
我的宝贝
My girl.
我的天啊
Oh,my.
真是亭亭玉立的大姑娘了
How pretty you've grown.
多漂亮的裙子啊
Such a lovely dress.
- 芙莱妮小姐买给我的 - 嗨
- Miss Phryne bought it for me. - Hello.
我是芙莱妮・费雪
I'm Phryne Fisher.
就是你一直在照顾简吧
You're the one who's been minding my Jane.
我没把你送到福利院 他们不可信
Didn't like to go to Welfare. You can't trust them.
但我病情一稳定就立马开始找你了
But once I got back on my feet,I started looking.
我 我在早报上看到你了
I... I saw you in the morning paper.
上面写着 费雪小姐的养女
Miss Fisher's ward,it says.
- 简・罗斯 - 是啊
- Jane Ross. - Yes.
简在我这儿已经有段时间了
Jane's been with me for quite some time now.
真的很感谢你把我女儿照顾的健康快乐
I thank you so very much for keeping my little girl safe and healthy.
乐意之极
It's been my absolute pleasure.
- 费雪小姐? - 我就是
- Miss Fisher? - That's me.
我不明白 小姐 不是说简的妈妈去世了么
I don't understand,Miss. I thought Jane's mother was dead.
我也这么以为
We all did,Dot.
如果我知道她妈仍健在
I would have never stepped in
我绝不会插手的
if I had the slightest inkling her mother was alive and well.
喝药
Medicinal.
这是在离凯蒂・佩斯尸体一百米处拾到的
It was found a hundred yards from Kitty Pace's body.
这把钥匙看起来有点故事
This key looks promising.
看来她不住在街上的房子里
Perhaps she wasn't living on the streets after all.
而应该是一个整日风吹日晒的地方
Somewhere exposed to the elements,though.
会不会只是被海水泡了?
Wouldn't that just be the saltwater,sir?
别急着下结论 看包的闩子
Not this quickly. Look at the latch on the bag.
这个粉底盒 还都在发光呢
The compact. All still gleaming.
还有这个 我觉得是啤酒杯垫
And I believe that is a beer coaster.
- 上面还写着点什么 - 是啊
- And there's something written on it. - So there is.
碎片应该都在这
All the pieces must be here.
你觉得我们能把它拼回来吗
Do you think we can put it together again?
- 我可以试一下 长官 - 不错
- I can try,sir. - Good.
很好
Good.
简?
Jane?
- 你妈妈呢? - 她有事走了
- Where's your mother? - She had to go.
- 去哪了? - 她没告诉我具体的
- Where? - She didn't give an address.
太荒唐了
But that's ridiculous.
- 都找到你了还走? - 她还会回来的
- After all this time? - She'll come back.
反正她知道我在哪
Now that she knows where I am.
我们需要谈一谈
We need to discuss this.
而且我们应该跟她谈一谈你的未来 简
And we need to discuss things with her,Jane,about your future.
我还有历史作业没做完
I have history homework to do.
她不能把简带走 是吧?
But she can't take Jane back. Can she?
是你收养了她
You adopted her.
我们当时没找到她
We couldn't find her,Dot.
也不能确认她是否还健在
And we couldn't verify her death either.
所以收养文件一直没正式签署
So the papers were never signed.
这个应该是个W
That's got to be a W.
肯定是W
Surely that's a W.
这个看起来更像N和W
That looks more like an N and a W.
那这个是什么呢?
Then what is that?
休
Hugh.
休 醒醒 我拼好了
Hugh,wake up. I'm finished.
威顿公司的麦酒?
Whitten's Pale Ale?
这是种澳大利亚南部的酒
That's a South Australian beer.
- 另一面写的是什么? - 全是名字
- What's on the other side? - Just a whole lot of names.
恩 你真聪明啊
Hmm,aren't you clever?
谢谢
Thank you.
小姐 我不知道您还没睡
I didn't know you were still up,Miss.
要为您来杯可可么?
Can I make you a cocoa?
我想今晚要喝一些更烈的东西 谢谢 桃乐西
I think I need something stronger tonight,thanks,Dot.
你完成了你的刑侦工作?
You finished your police work?
简说凯蒂 在大厅里晕倒过
Jane said Kitty fainted in the hall.
而且还让你帮她松了松裙子?
And didn't you have to let out the seams of her frock?
是的
That's right.
在腰腹部帮她
A couple of inches mostly around...
留了几英尺的空
mostly around the waist.
'爱德华 泰迪 埃德温...'
'Edward,Teddie,Edwin...'
可能是她的男性朋友?
Gentlemen friends?
这里也有女孩的名字
There's girls' names here too.
'埃德温娜 埃迪' 都是同一个名字变换的
'Edwina,Edie' - all variants of the same name.
我打赌凯蒂家里肯定有叫爱德华的人
I'll wager there was an Edward somewhere in Kitty's family tree.
是宝宝的名字
Babies' names.
宝宝的?
Babies.
什么宝宝?
What babies?
长官 佩斯小姐怀孕了么
Well,sir? Was Miss Pace expecting?
这样说吧 科林斯
Put it this way,Collins.
如果这个世界上全凭女性的直觉办事
If the world had any more womanly intuition,
- 那验尸官肯定都要下岗了 - 是啊
- the coroner would be out of a job. - Absolutely.
有查出死因吗?
And the cause of death?
他发现头骨后面有一个裂伤口
He notes a laceration to the back of the skull.
但是 胃里有大量的液体和碎屑
However,large quantities of fluid and debris in the stomach
充分证实了死者是溺水后死亡
strongly suggest death occurred subsequent to immersion.
- 这么说凶手不是萝丝 - 恩
- So Rose is off the hook. - Mmm.
而且凯蒂落水时还活着
And Kitty was alive when she drowned.
可以这么推断
That's the conclusion.
但是另有一处挫伤
But there was bruising suggestive of someone
是个比萝丝更强壮的人造成的
a lot more hefty than Rose Weston.
什么样的挫伤
What kind of bruising?
- 你无需知道 - 我必须知道
-You don't need to know. - Tell me.
在她的腰背部有个男性的鞋印
A man's boot print across the small of her back.
这个徽章很眼熟
That badge looks familiar.
这颜色
The colours.
'和谐源于真理'
'Concordium cum veritate.'
和谐源于真理
Harmony through truth.
非常赞成
I'm all for that.
简 下来了么?
Jane,are you coming?
我以为你都准备好了
I thought you were all ready?
这可是咱们最后一次彩排
It's our last rehearsal.
我不太舒服
I'm not feeling very well.
应该只是感冒了
I'm sure it's just a cold.
好吧 那回去睡会吧
Alright,back to bed with you.
德里克
Derek.
打扰一下 费雪小姐
Excuse me,Miss Fisher.
我应该把这些酒放哪里呢
Where would you like me to stack the refreshments?
德里克 我没听说过威顿牌的酒啊
Sorry,Derek. Whitten's. I haven't heard of that.
产自阿德莱德 顶级酿造
Ah,it's from Adelaide. Top brew.
看不出你年纪轻轻还是个行家
You're very young to be a beer connoisseur.
放厨房吧 谢谢
Kitchen will be fine,thank you.
我很喜欢你的校服 这校训是什么意思?
I was just intrigued by your school crest. What does the motto say?
是关于什么真理和谐之类的 是拉丁语
Something about truth and harmony. It's Latin.
我之前在一个校徽上也见过
I've seen it before. On a school badge.
嗯 是的 以前的那个被我弄丢了
Ah,yes. I used to own one. But I lost it.
警察帮你找到了 在凯蒂 佩斯的手包里
The police have found it. In Kitty Pace's handbag.
收拾好你的东西 德里克
Gather your things,Derek.
抱歉 姑娘们 今天花仙的事忙乎够了
Sorry,ladies. Enough maidenhood for one day.
我和德里克有点急事要处理
Derek and I have an urgent appointment.
德里克不会伤害凯蒂的
Derek wouldn't hurt Kitty.
他很爱她
He was sweet on her.
德里克不喜欢凯蒂
Derek wasn't sweet on Kitty.
他只是抵挡不了诱惑罢了
He just couldn't resist the other thing.
你懂的 下半身的诱惑
You know,down there.
你知道些什么啊? 嗯?
And what would you know? Hmm?
她身陷窘境 所以想趁机赖到他身上
She was trying to trap him because she was in strife.
我在房子后面看到她
I saw her out the back
正在呕吐 我立刻就懂了
heaving her guts out and I picked it right off.
她怀孕了
She was in the family way.
我把徽章给了玛丽
I gave that badge to Marie.
也许凯蒂因为嫉妒所以就拿走了
Maybe Kitty took it because she was jealous.
你要是真遵守校训的话 事情就简单多了
This'd be a lot easier if you stick to your school motto.
德里克 你穿几码的鞋?
What shoe size do you take,Derek?
十码 怎么了?
Size ten,why?
探长 我尽快赶来了
Inspector. I came as quickly as I could.
这么说你与凯蒂・佩斯没有任何瓜葛么?
So you weren't involved with Kitty Pace in any way?
是她极力想跟我有瓜葛
I think she wanted me to be.
她那天晚上邀我去一个海边浴屋见面
She asked me to meet her that night at one of the bathing sheds.
- 我想了想 - 就是她溺水的那晚?
-I thought about it. -The night she drowned?
但是我没有去
But I didn't go.
我去叔叔家听收音机听到很晚
I went to my Uncle's and listened to the wireless until late
- 然后还在那过夜了 - 是这样么?
- and then slept over. - Can you confirm this?
是的
Yes.
德里克来的时候我晚上正好还有个会要开
We had a late sitting at Council but when Derek arrived,
但我觉得他的事更要紧
I decided his visit was more important.
应该有人陪陪他
He seemed in need of company.
你当时知道凯蒂・佩斯怀孕了吗?
Did you know Kitty Pace was pregnant?
不 不 我不知道
No. No,I didn't.
小姐 别按了 你会把铃给弄坏的
Miss,steady on. You're going to wear out the bell.
告诉我 凯蒂有没有怀孕?
Tell me,please. Was Kitty expecting?
- 不如你先坐坐吧- 你先回答我?
- Perhaps you should take a seat. - Tell me,yes or no?
怎么了 警探?
What's going on out here,Constable?
维斯顿小姐想问一些关于凯蒂・佩斯的事
Miss Weston's enquiring about Kitty Pace,sir.
你稍等片刻吧 我这马上就完了
Well,I'm just finishing up if you'd like to wait.
不必了 没事
No,it's alright.
你说得对 这不关我事
You were right,it's none of my business.
- 萝丝? - 对不起打扰了
- Rose? - Sorry to bother you.
为什么萝丝这么惊慌失措的?
What was all that fuss about with Rose?
也许她也喜欢德里克吧
Maybe she holds a torch for Derek too.
虽然我看不出他到底哪有魅力了
Though I can't see what the attraction is myself.
可能是校服控吧
Could be a man in uniform.
拿上小桶和铲子吧 同志们
Get your buckets and spades,boys.
我想我们得去海边玩一趟
I think another trip to the seaside's in order.
继续试试白门 科林斯
Keep going. White door,Collins.
是的 就是这个 长官
Yeah,this is the one,sir.
不错的藏身所啊
Nice hideaway.
你看又是这种酒 先生
Here's that beer again,sir.
是的 正是德里克推荐的酒
Yes,Derek Philips recommends it.
看来我们得再找他聊聊了
We may need another chat with that young man.
文法学校的乖学生 还是个高官子弟
Good Grammar boy. Head Prefect to boot.
这种男孩最爱找没身份的野姑娘
Just the sort to sow his wild oats with a bad girl
然后放荡一番了
from the wrong side of the tracks,
结果一遇到点麻烦就怂了
only to panic at the first sign of trouble.
一把男士剃须刀
A gentleman's razor.
看来 德里克并不是凯蒂唯一的男性访客
Looks like Derek wasn't Kitty's only male visitor.
他这么小还用不着剃须呢
He's barely old enough to shave.
亨利・劳森:澳大利亚著名诗人 作家
你还是亨利・劳森的忠实读者呢
I didn't know you were a Henry Lawson fan.
现在好点了么?
How are you feeling?
好多了 我想搭电车去看看萝丝
Much better. I thought I'd catch the tram to see Rose.
今天有些晚了吧 ?
It's a bit late in the day,isn't it?
她因为凯蒂的事情很是伤心
She's been so upset about Kitty.
你不如明天再去 等不了多久的
I think it can wait until tomorrow. You'll see her soon enough.
不要 停下来好么? 我不能这样
No,stop it,OK? I can't do this.
我满脑子想的都是她 抱歉
I can't stop thinking about her. I'm sorry.
你是该觉得抱歉 因为我不干了
You will be sorry because the deal's off.
我不会帮你撒谎掩护了!
I'm not covering for you anymore!
不 等等 玛丽!
No,wait! Marie!
妈妈? 是我 简
Mother? It's me. Jane.
我就知道你会如约过来的 你总是说到做到
I knew you'd come like you promised. You always keep your word.
进来吧
Come in.
我带了一些文件需要你签字
I've brought some papers I need you to sign.
收养文件
Adoption Documents
我还是会常来看你的
Don't think I won't visit.
我保证
I will.
只不过还是这样更好
But it's better this way.
嗯 我明白
Yeah,I know.
别担心
Don't worry.
我还带了些你可能需要的东西
I brought you some things you might need.
买日常用品的钱
Money for shopping.
还有本书
A book.
亨利・劳森 我们可以像原来一样一块念书
Henry Lawson. We can read them together like we used to.
就一小会儿 怎么样?
Just for a short while,hmm?
谁?
Hello?
是你么?
Is that you?
你来这里干嘛?
What are you doing here?
"跋山涉水 翻山越岭
'In deep ways and steep ways and high ways and low,
我在陌生的路上觉得安逸而不拘
I'm at home and at ease on a track that I know not,
却在熟悉的路上觉得迷失和不安"
and restless and lost on a road that I know.'
现在 我们还得来点下午茶
Now,all we need is some afternoon tea,
像原来一样 还记得么?
like we used to make,remember?
但现在已经是晚上了
But it's late. It's night-time.
没关系的
No matter.
我做个蛋糕来庆祝一下
I'll bake us a cake to celebrate.
你向来喜欢吃我做的苹果蛋糕
You always loved my apple cake.
很快就好了
It'll be done before you know it.
我天亮之前必须回去
I have to be back before morning.
当然了
Of course you do.
奇怪了 貌似家用不太够了
Odd,I don't seem to have enough housekeeping money.
看来我们家的小扒手们日渐猖狂
Maybe our light-fingered visitors are becoming more daring.
你看见了简吗?
Have you seen Jane?
她不在楼上 床还跌的整整齐齐
She's not upstairs and her bed's made.
- 早安 - 早安 !
- Morning! - Morning.
到处都找不到简 小姐
I can't seem to find Jane anywhere,Miss.
她是不是早起去上学了?
Do you know if she left early for school?
两个都没去?
Both of them?
是啊 的确很奇怪 但我相信肯定没什么大事
Yes,it is odd but I'm sure there'll be some simple explanation.
谢谢
Thank you.
萝丝今天也没有去学校
Rose hasn't shown up for school either.
玛丽说你定期会和凯蒂会面
Marie said you were meeting Kitty regularly.
每周两次 在海边的小浴屋
Twice a week at the bathing shed.
我翘掉了辩论小组
Instead of debating practice.
而且我是真心爱她
And I loved her,I did.
但是她想让我退学和她结婚
But she wanted me to leave school to marry her.
这太疯狂了
It all seemed so mad.
然后你怎么做的?
So what did you do?
她那晚要我给她个准信
She wanted an answer that night.
但我跟我叔叔交代了我俩的事
But I told my uncle that I was mixed up with her
叔叔让我离她远点 我并不知道她怀孕了
and he said to stay away. I didn't know Kitty was pregnant.
而且我绝对没有杀她
And I certainly didn't  kill her.
但是...我的确不该撒谎
But... I just feel so wretched that I lied.
还让别人帮我圆谎
And other people had to lie for me.
比如谁呢?
Like who?
玛丽说她会替我撒谎
Marie said she would back what I said
说我把校徽给了她
about giving her my school badge
而且叔叔也愿意为我提供不在场证明
and I needed my uncle as an alibi.
他当时没和我在一起 他去开会了
He wasn't with me. He was at a meeting.
你认识凯蒂多长时间了?
How long had you known Kitty?
六周吧
Six weeks.
凯蒂至少有了三个月的身孕了 德里克
Kitty was at least three months pregnant,Derek.
这么说孩子不是我的
So it wasn't mine.
打扰了 长官 你应该看看这份
Ah,excuse me,sir. You might like to know the result
关于沙滩浴屋所属人的文件
of that Titles search on that bathing shed.
我从来没去过浴屋那
I never go near the shed.
在一场赌博中 我输掉了我的船和所有的一切
I lost my boat,along with everything else,in a card game.
你的家具也是因此消失了
That would explain your disappearing furniture.
听着 我完全不知道凯蒂 佩斯在那里住
Look,I had no idea Kitty Pace was living there.
我可以向你保证
I give you my word.
像你这样输得精光的人 维斯顿先生
A man who has lost as much money as you have,Mr Weston,
是会不择手段寻找补救机会的
is willing to embrace all kinds of opportunities,
- 甚至不惜犯法 - 我不明白你什么意思
- not all of them legal.- I don't know what you're implying.
你把凯蒂・佩斯安置在那是为了图自己方便
Did you set Kitty Pace up there for your own convenience
还是为了给其他男人也提供方便?
or perhaps the convenience of other gentlemen?
维斯顿先生 !
Mr Weston!
我一直想给你打电话 维斯顿先生
I've been trying to telephone you,Mr Weston.
我在找我的女儿 萝丝在哪里?
I'm looking for my daughter. Where's Rose?
- 她在学校 - 不 她没有
- She's at school. - No,she's not.
简也没去学校 两个女孩子都失踪了
Neither is Jane. Both girls are missing.
- 她们能去哪里呢?- 我不知道
- Where could they be? - I have no idea.
萝丝给我留了字条 但是我没有在意
Rose left me a note but I didn't take it seriously.
萝丝昨晚把字条放在门阶上了
Rose left this on the doorstep last night.
但是包 衣服 钱她什么都没拿
But she didn't take her bag,clothes,money,nothing.
所以我觉得她肯定会回来
So naturally I assumed she'd be back.
但这张字条上写她不想继续这样了
But this says that she doesn't want to go on.
- 你认为简和她在一起 - 我不知道
- Do you think Jane's with her?- I don't know.
我只想尽快找到她俩
I just want to find them both. Fast.
萝丝能去哪里呢?
Where would Rose go?
她喜欢海滩 海滩浴屋
Well,she liked the beach. The bathing sheds.
我看见有人在里面 快点!
I can see someone. Hurry up!
天啊! 她做了什么傻事?
Oh,God! What has she done?
安眠药
Sleeping pills.
- 她还有气儿吗 ? - 一点点
- Is she breathing?- Just.
萝丝 萝丝 你听得见我说话么?
Rose! Rose,can you hear me?
醒过来啊 萝丝 醒过来吧
Come on,Rose,come on.
求你了!
Please!
- 是他逼我的 - 什么?
- He made me do it. - What?
- 谁 ? - 他逼我这样的
- Who? - He made me do it.
好了 我们把她抬出去
Alright,let's get her out of here.
一 二 三
One,two,three.
- 她没什么大碍吧? - 她很幸运
- Is she alright? - She was lucky.
护士把她胃里的药都给清空了
They pumped what they could out of her stomach.
她现在只要睡过了药效就好了
She just has to sleep the rest off.
- 还是没有简的消息么? - 嗯
- Still no news of Jane? - No.
看来她俩没在一起
It doesn't seem like they were together.
你看过抽屉了么?
Did you check the bureau?
是 是的 你说得对
Y-yes and you were right.
收养文件不见了
The adoption papers are gone.
我现在要回警察局
I'm going back to the police station.
做好了
It's done.
起床吧
Wake up.
一切都准备好了
Everything's ready.
- 怎么了? - 没事
- What's wrong? - Nothing.
真是一团糟 怎么回事?
It's all wrong. But why is it?
一定有人在捣鬼
Someone must have tampered with it.
你一定是把盐和糖搞混了
You must have used salt instead of sugar.
不可能 肯定是有人在这屋子里捣鬼
But I didn't. Someone's been in here.
- 不会的- 不 是他干的
- No,they haven't. - Yes,they have. It's him.
我前些天也听见他的动静了
I heard him the other night.
他有段时间没来这里了
He hasn't been around here for a while.
放错了盐是个凶兆 你还记得洛特的妻子么
It's a bad omen to spill salt. Do you remember Lot's wife?
记得么? 我们得把盐往肩上洒辟邪
Remember? We've got to throw some over our shoulder.
你需要休息
You need some sleep.
还有 我得回家了 她们会担心我的
A-and I need to go home. They'll be worried.
但是你不能走 出去就不安全了 过来
But you can't. It's not safe out there. Here.
我得走了 钥匙在哪里?
I need to go. Where's the key?
是他啊 简 你还不明白么?
It's him,Jane. Don't you understand?
把门打开 拜托!
Unlock the door. Please!
安娜! 我知道你在里面
Anna! I know you're in there.
简・罗斯 十四岁 母亲的名字是安娜・罗斯
Jane Ross,14 years old. Mother's name is Anna Ross.
假若她没和她妈妈在一起怎么办?
What if she's not with her mother?
假如逼萝丝服药的人也对简做同样的事怎么办
What if the same person who drugged Rose has Jane as well
- 一直以来.. - 冷静 芙莱妮
- and all this time... - Calm down,Phryne.
你记得被你收养钱她什么样吧
You remember what she was like before you rescued her.
简是最会在逆境里照顾好自己的人了
If anyone knows how to look after themselves on the street,it's Jane.
我不知此事是否有关联
I'm not sure if this is relevant,sir,
但是委员会证实
but the Council confirmed
维斯顿先生的确由于赌博丢了工作
Mr Weston lost office due to his gambling.
尽管市长尽力想让他复职
Though the Mayor is trying to get him reinstated.
为什么市长要费劲帮一个这样的人?
Why would he bother trying to help a man like that?
警探 看看你能不能拖住时间了
See if you can get hold of the minutes,Constable.
城南警局 对的
City South. Yeah,that's right.
在罗斯堂大街 谢谢
In Rathdowne Street. Thank you.
卡尔顿警方接到一个罗斯夫人的电话
Carlton Police had a call to check on a Mrs Ross.
说在一家公寓发生了点家庭纠纷
Some domestic dispute at a boarding house.
安娜 是我啦! 你打算在里面待多久?
Anna,it's me again! How long are you going to stay in there?
噢 放弃吧! 开门吧!
Oh,give up! Unlock it!
- 放弃吧 你这个婊子! - 嘿 警察!
- Give up,you trollop! - Hey! Police!
嘿 冷静点 我是房东
Hey,steady on,I'm the landlord.
她把自己反锁在里面 我都闻见煤气味了
She's bloody locked herself in and I can smell gas.
- 简! - 让开点
- Jane! - Out of the way.
帮帮我! 快来!
Help me! Please!
我在外面! 她要跳下去了!
Out here! She's going to jump!
简! 坚持住!
Jane! Hold on!
- 等等 等等 - 快点!
- Wait,wait. - Please!
帮帮我!
Help me!
没事了
It's alright.
你现在安全了
You're safe now.
我很抱歉 但我必须把她赶出去
I'm sorry but I'll have to evict her.
你看 她人都不清醒!
I mean,she's not full quid!
默里 我对你的想法没兴趣
I'm not interested in your opinion,Murray.
你得跟我走一趟 快走
You're coming with me to the station. Move.
快点
Now.
来吧
Come on.
她不肯...她不肯听我的
She wouldn't... She wouldn't listen to me.
我试过了 她其实人不坏
I tried. She's not mean.
她...她只是需要我
She... She just needs me.
我很抱歉没有告诉你
I'm sorry I didn't tell you.
- 罗斯夫人 要添茶吗? - 谢谢
- More tea,Mrs Ross? - Thank you.
我感觉好多了 你的房子真漂亮
I feel so much better. Such a beautiful home you have here.
噢 这不是我的房子
Oh,it's not mine,really.
但这里欢迎每一个人 包括你罗斯夫人
But everyone is welcome including you,Mrs Ross.
噢 像画里的花仙子
Oh,what a picture.
真是女大十八变了
You've grown into a wonderful young lady.
桃乐西 你可以带罗斯夫人上楼洗个澡吗?
Dot,would you like to take Mrs Ross up for her bath?
噢!
Oh!
真体贴
How lovely.
他们会再把她关起来的 人们会伤害她的
They'll lock her up again and people will hurt her.
我去过那些地方的 她还能去哪呢?
I've been to those places. Where can she go?
我们会找到一个她喜欢待的地方
We'll find somewhere where she's happy.
而且你还能随时见她
And you can visit her whenever you like.
我保证
I promise.
你好 探长
Hello,Inspector.
你应该会想知道
You might like to know why
为什么维斯顿先生没有在委员会复职吧
Mr Weston wasn't reinstated to Council.
委员会在凯蒂溺水那晚对复职一事进行了投票
They put it to the vote the night Kitty Pace was drowned.
而市长并未出席 尽管他不承认
And Mayor Phillips,despite all his lobbying,was absent.
但德里克说他俩不在一起啊
But Derek said he wasn't with him.
那他在哪里呢?
So where was he?
萝丝 谁逼你服药的?
Rose,who made you take all those pills?
和杀凯蒂的是同一个人吗?
Was it the same person who killed Kitty?
和你那天在警局躲着的是同一个人么?
Was it the same person you ran from at the police station?
当你祖父失势时 没有人愿意帮他
The Mayor helped your grandfather when he was disgraced
只有市长帮了他
when no-one else would.
为什么他要那样做?
Why would he do that?
那天你惊慌的离家出走也是因为他吧
It was the Mayor who was there when you ran away in fear.
就是那个热心选出花仙小姐的市长
And the Mayor who was so helpful choosing all the flower maidens.
萝丝 是他强迫你写那张纸条的吗?
Did he force you to write that note,Rose?
他把凯蒂安置在那间老浴屋里
He set Kitty up in our old bathing shed.
他付她钱 这样就能随时去找她
He paid her money so he could visit whenever he felt like it.
但凯蒂不想干了 她想告发他让他出丑
But Kitty changed her mind. She wanted to tell on him,disgrace him.
这就是我们争吵的事
That's what we argued about.
但当我发现凯蒂怀孕时 我就知道原因了
But when I found out Kitty was pregnant,I knew why.
我知道是市长溺死她的
I knew it was the Mayor who drowned her.
这都是我的错
It's all my fault.
我应该当机立断听凯蒂的去告发他
I should have told on him when Kitty wanted me to.
他说我很聪明很漂亮
He said I was clever and pretty.
他送我礼物
He bought me presents.
他借我们钱
He loaned us money.
他想让我做他真正的女友
He wanted me to be his proper girlfriend.
我们只发生过一次关系
It only happened once.
然后祖父向他介绍了凯蒂
And then grandfather introduced him to Kitty
她取代我变成了他的情人
and she became his girlfriend instead.
噢 萝丝
Oh,Rose.
维斯顿先生来见她的孙女
Mr Weston is here to see his granddaughter.
请他进来
Show him in.
萝丝告诉了我们一切
Rose has told us everything.
你不惜出卖自己的孙女来还债
You sold your granddaughter so you could pay your debts.
然后又推凯蒂进火坑
And then let Kitty suffer instead.
市长想杀死萝丝并伪装成自杀事件
The Mayor tried to murder Rose and make it look like suicide.
萝丝 对不起
I'm so sorry,Rose.
请你 请你原谅我
Please,please forgive me.
费雪小姐
Miss Fisher.
他就是那个人
He's the one.
他就是那个想杀我的人
He's the one who tried to kill me.
莱昂内尔・菲利普斯市长 你被逮捕了
Mayor Lionel Phillips,you're under arrest.
你居然相信这个不良少女的证词?
You accept the word of this troubled young girl?
维斯顿小姐和她的祖父提供了完整详细的口供
Miss Weston and her grandfather gave a full and detailed statement.
你被控告绑架 多次猥亵少女
You're charged with kidnap,various indecency charges,
谋杀未遂 和谋杀凯瑟琳・佩斯小姐
attempted murder and the murder of Miss Katherine Pace.
萝丝 干得好 到车里面等我 我很快就来
Well done,Rose. Wait for me in the car,I won't be long.
看来我开设的社交礼仪课程简直就是场灾难
Well,my school of social graces was a complete disaster.
看来这镇里有不少老狐狸觊觎那些年轻姑娘
There are enough fox trotting young ladies in this town.
你教会了她们追求正义
You taught them to demand justice instead.
毫无疑问她们此后会维护自己权益
And no doubt they'll all become firebrands in their own right
努力改变世界的 上帝保佑
and try to change the world,God help us.
噢 这是简的收养文件
Oh. Janie's adoption papers,
有一点皱了
a little the worse for wear.
谢谢你
Thank you.
但简的母亲永远是她的母亲
But Jane's mother will always be her mother.
那你是什么? 她的守护天使吗?
And what will you be? Her guardian angel?
这倒是挺像我的风格的
Much more my style.